<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-20T15:27:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">This Week in Learning</title><subtitle>Learning for Learning's Sake.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Muay Thai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/14/muay-thai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Muay Thai" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/14/muay-thai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/14/muay-thai.html">&lt;p&gt;Muay Thai, the art of eight limbs, but also known as simply “Thai boxing,” is a devastatingly effective martial art of Thailand characterized by the combined use of fists, elbows, knees and shins. In recent years, competitions in Muay Thai have spread throughout the western world and many foreigners from the U.S., Europe, South America, etc. travel to Thailand for personal training with individuals who have trained in the art since their childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inscriptions from stone columns at the Buddhist temples of &lt;a href=&quot;livesafely.org/main/wp-content/uploads/MuayThai-book.pdf&quot;&gt;Sukhothai&lt;/a&gt; (Thailand’s capital from 1238-1409 CE) indicate frequent conflict with neighboring countries Burma and Cambodia. Thus, the city required its soldiers to not only master the use of swords and spears, but also weaponize the body in close person-to-person combat. By the Great Era (1590-1604 CE), King Naresuan of Thailand established a corps of worthy young warriors skilled with weapons and boxing to fight a guerilla war against Burma and subsequently freed Thailand from Burmese oppression. Following the victory, Thailand experienced several years of peace and, in this time, Muay Thai was promoted as sport both for youth development and cultural entertainment. Boxing rings were established in playgrounds and the boxers learned to wrap their hands with cloth dipped in a thick tar for protection. The boxers would don a mongkon head band and pa-pra-jiat amulets wrapped around each of their upper arms during a fight. A boxing bout typically involved gambling and the fight did not end until there was a clear winner. As the sport evolved, villages would often challenge one another to Muay Thai matches and the activity became a central event of all folk plays and festivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/muay-thai/pic 1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excerpt from the book &lt;em&gt;Muay Thai, the Art of Fighting&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;“During the early part of the Ayutthaya period the Department of Royal Boxing was founded. One of its responsibilities was to recruit young talented boxers to fight for the King’s entertainment. The top boxers were chosen for the Royal Quarries, called Thani Lir (chosen guards). They were responsible for the security of the royal palace and the King at all times. These boxers were to become the boxing masters who trained the soldiers and the Princes. In the later part of the Ayutthaya Period, after the second loss to Burma in B.E. 2310 (1767 CE), there was one boxer of note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nai Khanomtom was a prisoner of war captured by the Burmese when Ayutthaya was sacked for the second time in B.E. 2310 (1767 CE). In B.E. 2317 (1774 CE), the Burmese King, King Angwa, wanted to hold a celebration for the Great Pagoda in Rangoon. Boxing was included in the celebrations. Good Thai boxers were called on to fight with Burmese boxers. On the 17th of March of that year, Nai Khanomtom fought and defeated 10 Burmese boxers in succession with no rest period between fights. It was the first time that MuayThai was used in competition outside of Thailand. For his achievements, Nai Khanomtom was honored as the Father or MuayThai or the Inventor of MuayThai, and the 17th of March is now named Muay Thai Day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a Muay Thai bout begins, each boxer performs a “Wai Khru Ram Muay” to honor their boxing teacher, their parents and their ancestors. As a sport formerly performed for the royalty, the Wai Khru would have also included an honoring of the king, however the main intent of the ritual is to formalize the student-teacher relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5bjvCp6u2H4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/muay-thai/pic 2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a Wai Khru Ram Muay, each boxer enters and circles the ring in a counter-clockwise direction and prays at each corner, accompanied by rhythmic &lt;em&gt;Sarama&lt;/em&gt; music. The boxer bows their head at each corner three times to salute Buddha, Rama and the sangha of monks, then begins the Ram Muay, a personal ritual that involves specific movements that can contain clues about the boxer’s trainer or where the boxer is from. The movements also function as a pre-fight warm-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many say that the sport today is brutal and violent and this would be true. Injuries from Muay Thai, like other forms of boxing, can result in disastrous forms of head trauma. Most problematic of all, child boxers of Muay Thai, who, due to a combination of inadequate regulation, cultural pressure and absent reporting, are subject to brain injuries before the age of 15; some even as young as nine years old. As a result, there has been an immense national pushback against the pressure for young children to compete in Thai boxing. An article from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thethaiger.com/news/national/the-worst-type-of-child-abuse-doctors-call-on-ban-for-underage-boxing&quot;&gt;The Thaiger&lt;/a&gt; includes a statistic from the 13th World Conference on Injury Prevention and Safety Promotion that unless a law is created banning children under 12 from competing in Muay Thai matches, approximately 3% of the new generation will sustain learning disabilities. The exact meaning of the term “new generation” is unclear, however it remains that the culture of Muay Thai does not come without dangers to each and every boxer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Muay Thai exists as a source of great pride for Thailand and its roots of historical combat against oppressors are not forgotten. Muay Thai has influenced martial arts around the world and it has become widely accepted as the most effective, albeit vicious, striking martial art of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://livesafely.org/main/wp-content/uploads/MuayThai-book.pdf&quot;&gt;Muay Thai, The Art of Fighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fightland.vice.com/blog/muay-thai-photographing-the-roots-and-culture-of-thailands-greatest-tradition&quot;&gt;Vice, Fightland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cienciadotreinamento.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FOOT-AND-ANKLE-PROBLEMS-IN-MUAY-THAI-KICKBOXERS.pdf&quot;&gt;Foot and Ankle Problems in Muay Thai Kickboxers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thethaiger.com/news/national/the-worst-type-of-child-abuse-doctors-call-on-ban-for-underage-boxing&quot;&gt;The Thaiger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Mathis</name></author><summary type="html">Muay Thai, the art of eight limbs, but also known as simply “Thai boxing,” is a devastatingly effective martial art of Thailand characterized by the combined use of fists, elbows, knees and shins. In recent years, competitions in Muay Thai have spread throughout the western world and many foreigners from the U.S., Europe, South America, etc. travel to Thailand for personal training with individuals who have trained in the art since their childhood.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/muay-thai.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chicago Stockyards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/chicago-stockyards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chicago Stockyards" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/chicago-stockyards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/chicago-stockyards.html">&lt;p&gt;My dad’s dad turned 80 this past June and decided to move out of his house in Lake Zurich, IL and in with my aunt and uncle’s family a few hours south in Peoria. I grew up down the street from my grandparents, and even though my parents moved across town a few years ago and I’ve spent the last few years all over the place, it happened that I was in my hometown in early September when my grandpa moved away; and that meant that it fell to my dad and I to sell or throw away most of his possessions and fix up the house to rent or sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my grandpa, Robert, was born the third of five children in 1938, the coattails of the Great Depression, on a farm in rural Illinois. In those times going into the town a few miles away was a serious ordeal, a trek that nowadays would feel akin to driving from Chicago to Milwaukee at 80 miles an hour. You wouldn’t go into town for just anything—some measly nails, say—and that meant that people kept the most absurd assortment of items lying around just in case they might be useful at some point. My grandpa grew up with that tendency towards austerity, and it has stuck with him for his whole life. This is all to say that he had heaps of what you and I might call junk stored in the garage, basement, and attic; but in sifting through all his stuff in order to decide what to sell, save, or toss, we unearthed a few unexpected treasures, including a stack of receipts from the 1950s from the Chicago Union Stockyards. We decided to keep the receipts—they’re only a shade bigger than a notecard—and the next month I decided to reach out to my grandpa and find out what he knew about the Chicago Stockyards through his and his family’s experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/chicago-stockyards/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1864, nine railroad companies joined forces to buy 320 acres of land just south of the city, forming the Union Stock Yard &amp;amp; Transit Company. There were already several smaller meat markets in the city at the time, but there was widespread clamor from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Droving&quot;&gt;drovers&lt;/a&gt;, dealers, and farmers that all expounded the importance of a common center for the whole livestock trade in the city. Chicago — though at the time the population of the city was only 75,000 — was a natural junction for all of the agricultural Midwest that shipped their wares farther east. The land was flat and it was well connected to major waterways through Lake Michigan and the Chicago River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Christmas Day in 1865 the Stockyards were opened, and experienced continual growth through the rest of the century. Though the Stockyards were originally used just as a place to route livestock through, by 1870 meatpacking companies had arrived on the scene and the Stockyards became a butchery too. By 1900 the Stockyards alone employed 25,000 people, and 40,000 by 1921. Chicago’s population was over 1.6 million at the turn of the century, not to mention the thousands of railroad workers and farmers who sold their livestock at the markets there, like my grandpa’s family. The Yards had room for around 120,000 live cows, hogs and sheep at any given time; in 1900 it processed 82 percent of the meat consumed in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/chicago-stockyards/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real success of the Union Stockyards can be most directly attributed to the expansion of the United States’ railroads: to put it in perspective, the Transcontinental Railroad was completed in 1869, just a few short years after the Stockyards opened. By the end of the 1860s refrigerated boxcars were becoming practical too, and these allowed meat to be dressed before being forwarded to retailers, meaning more meat could be shipped at once. And in response to the exploding meat market in Chicago, other businesses opened: wool processors, glue makers, and tanneries, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1953 Robert took on the responsibility of managing the hogs from his father. He was a sophomore in high school. They lived outside of a rural town named Forrest, where his family had already rented 80 acres under a landlord/tenant agreement for generations. According to Robert’s memory, the landlord received half the annual harvested crop, and the other half was for the tenant. His dad used a portion of his allotted half for animal feed — for dairy cows and calves, hogs, and chickens — though the arrangement depended on having the grain available, as needed, to sustain feeding the animals. Robert did not personally deliver hogs, but did sell them to an agent who put together several smaller lots and then sold them to one of the meat-packers in Chicago. They were transported by a local Forrest-area trucker who periodically made the run and delivered them to each shipper’s designated agent. Robert was following this method used by his dad, who learned it from his dad before him, and so on back to the 1860s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Robert was a senior in high school in 1956, he must have seen the writing on the wall, because he decided to attend a small college just over the border into Indiana to study engineering instead of continuing to work the family farm: a mere fifteen years later, the Chicago Stockyards closed. It’s decline was brought about by much the same thing that made all its early success possible: further developments in transportation and distribution, namely the Interstate Highway System whose construction began in 1956. It became cheaper and simpler to slaughter animals near where they were raised, so breeders began selling their livestock directly to local meatpackers who could ship it on refrigerated trucks from their own factories which they built in rural areas, essentially cutting out the Stockyards as an intermediary. But when the Stockyards closed in 1971, Chicago had already gone through its growth spurt, the transformation from an unknown prairie city to the second most populous city in the U.S. (at the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/chicago-stockyards/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of my research I stumbled upon a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/video/chicago-tonight-december-20-2011-chicagos-union-stockyards-40-years/&quot;&gt;segment of a short film&lt;/a&gt; that a university student made on the last day the Stockyards were open. He interviewed workers, some of whom were old men who had worked there for over fifty years, and whose fathers had worked there during the prior century. Even those grizzled veterans couldn’t help but feel nostalgic about the place. “They’re beautiful memories in the past,” one of them remarked, “but very sad today.” And it’s no wonder: the Stockyards didn’t just shape the lives of the people who worked there, but the city of Chicago too. Nowadays, at least to me, Chicago seems rather disjointed when compared to the U.S.’s other giants: New York, with a history as rich as and older than the United States itself; and Los Angeles in the golden, fruitful West. I grew up in Chicago’s shadow, right on the edge of the suburbs where rural Illinois begins, but could never quite figure out what 10 million people were doing there. But the city’s roots are in the U.S.’s agricultural past — in the Union Stockyards; and how could such a monument do anything but attract people to it? Am I really that surprised, after all, that Robert held on to all those receipts for 65 years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/video/chicago-tonight-december-20-2011-chicagos-union-stockyards-40-years/&quot;&gt;https://www.pbs.org/video/chicago-tonight-december-20-2011-chicagos-union-stockyards-40-years/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/technology-that-changed-chicago-union-stockyards-part-one/&quot;&gt;https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/technology-that-changed-chicago-union-stockyards-part-one/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagoist.com/2012/08/01/one_for_the_road_75.php#photo-1&quot;&gt;http://chicagoist.com/2012/08/01/one_for_the_road_75.php#photo-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Knapp, Joseph G. “A Review of Chicago Stock Yards History.” The University Journal of Business, vol. 2, no. 3, 1924, pp. 331–346. JSTOR, JSTOR, www.jstor.org/stable/2354664.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Other Contributors</name></author><summary type="html">My dad’s dad turned 80 this past June and decided to move out of his house in Lake Zurich, IL and in with my aunt and uncle’s family a few hours south in Peoria. I grew up down the street from my grandparents, and even though my parents moved across town a few years ago and I’ve spent the last few years all over the place, it happened that I was in my hometown in early September when my grandpa moved away; and that meant that it fell to my dad and I to sell or throw away most of his possessions and fix up the house to rent or sell.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/chicago-stockyards.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mushroom Remediation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/16/mushroom-remediation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mushroom Remediation" /><published>2018-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/16/mushroom-remediation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/16/mushroom-remediation.html">&lt;p&gt;Chicago, and the Rust Belt more generally, is full of former industrial sites, now-vacant properties that manufacturers gradually abandoned over the second half of the 20th century. The flight of industrial capital for cheaper environs destroyed entire communities of laborers, like the steelworkers on the city’s Southwest Side; it also left residents to cope with the damaging environmental effects those factories created for the earth they worked on. (Of course, there’s also plenty of dangerous pollution still taking place.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some sites, the EPA has engaged in remediation, cleaning up the land, air, and water to hopefully allow for other uses. There are also some cases where the EPA has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investigativepost.org/2017/08/23/feds-pull-plug-on-radioactive-remediation/&quot;&gt;halted work&lt;/a&gt;, and, generally, there is perhaps good reason to distrust the Trump administration’s willingness, particularly on a region-by-region basis, to perform the necessary degree of environmental rehabilitation. For those and other reasons, plenty of amateur agriculturists are engaging in their own backyard bioremediation — using living organisms to try to remove toxins from the ecosystems they live and work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I want to talk a little about fungal bioremediation. I first heard about it when I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://southsideweekly.com/soil-and-sovereignty-viviana-gentry-fernandez-pellon-pullman/&quot;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; in the South Side Weekly with a farmer about rehabilitating parts of the Cooperation Operation, a big, beautiful community garden in Pullman. The Coop Op was started about half a decade ago; before then, it had been a liquid hazardous waste facility. The EPA did some cleanup on the site — in fact, they settled for around $36,000 with 42 corporations in 2004 to help with waste removal. (In case you’re keeping score at home, or are perhaps wondering about possible causes of widespread civil unrest, that means each company had to pay a little under $1,000, and the EPA waived $200,000 in earlier response costs). Anyway, this farmer decided to ask for public records, and discovered there were still fairly high levels of lead, cadmium, arsenic, and “petroleum-based stuff.” So they decided that they should try their own remediation using mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how exactly does fungal bioremediation work? Well, to begin with, fungi have, as one academic puts it, “everted stomachs”: whereas we humans decompose our food into nutrients inside of ourselves, in a sac that sits along our digestive system, fungi break down food &lt;em&gt;externally&lt;/em&gt;, turning it into nutrients before ingestion. They do this by releasing enzymes into the environment around them through their mycelia — long, branching networks of filaments called hyphae, “the basic fungal unit.” Interestingly, even though larger patterns of growth and reproduction are present in mushrooms, the mycelial networks themselves are protean and indeterminate, forever changing their configuration in response to stimuli around them. (“Determinate superstructure is integrated by indeterminate infrastructure,” is how the mycologist Alan D.M. Rayner phrases this point.)
Depending on the extracellular enzymes a particular mushroom releases, they can break down pretty much any substance into simple non-toxic compounds or inorganic matter. Oyster mushrooms have been used to dissolve plastics and crude oil; the splitgill can decompose malachite green; shiitake disappears petroleum compounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of other processes by which fungi can also remove toxins from an ecosystem. One is biosorption — the removal of substances from a solution or environment by means of biological material. Fungi are particularly useful for this because their cell walls are about 10% chitin, the tough polymer that’s also, as you probably learned in high school, found in the exoskeletons of crustaceans. Chitins have amines, which are particularly good at bonding with metal ions; that makes mushrooms useful in cleaning up pollution from heavy metals. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scielo.br/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;amp;pid=S1517-83822004000200013&quot;&gt;A study&lt;/a&gt; that extracted chitin and its chemical cousin, chitosan, from the fungus &lt;em&gt;Cuninghamella elegans&lt;/em&gt; found that they could absorb between 25 and 75 percent of iron, lead, and copper from the environment. (And, even if we can’t grow mushrooms in a particular environment, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omicsonline.org/open-access/utilization-of-industrial-microbe-side-streams-for-biosorption-of-heavy-metals-from-wastewaters-2155-6199-1000285.php?aid=50366&quot;&gt;easier&lt;/a&gt; to extract chitin from fungi than it is to get it from crustaceans.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you wanted to engage in some backyard remediation (or just, you know, grow mushrooms) — where would you start? The grassroots organization Radical Mycology has put together a helpful guide &lt;a href=&quot;https://radicalmycology.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/mushroom-cultivation-for-remediation-computer-read.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Most fundamentally, you need a really large mycelium, and the best way to get that is by force-feeding the fungus. There are a few different stages here: start the fungal culture in a sugary water broth, move it to a container full of grains (the RM zine recommends rye, wheat berries, spelt, millet, or popcorn[!]), and finish growing it in cooked hardwood sawdust, usually from alder or maple. Once you’ve done all that, you continue growing the mycelium in what the guide calls “bunker spawn” — bags of fermented straw and wood chips. Once they’ve grown in there for a few months, you can use them to filter pollutants out of water, remediate soil, or create stability in any ground threatened by erosion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christian Belanger</name></author><summary type="html">Chicago, and the Rust Belt more generally, is full of former industrial sites, now-vacant properties that manufacturers gradually abandoned over the second half of the 20th century. The flight of industrial capital for cheaper environs destroyed entire communities of laborers, like the steelworkers on the city’s Southwest Side; it also left residents to cope with the damaging environmental effects those factories created for the earth they worked on. (Of course, there’s also plenty of dangerous pollution still taking place.)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/mushroom-remediation.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Microphone Types and How They Work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/25/microphone-types-explained.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microphone Types and How They Work" /><published>2018-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/25/microphone-types-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/25/microphone-types-explained.html">&lt;p&gt;In this post, I set out to explain two basic types of microphones and how they work. This post is in some ways a successor to my previous post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisweekinlearning.com/2018/09/08/signal-processing.html&quot;&gt;signal processing and flow&lt;/a&gt;; if you didn’t read that one already, and you have a spare few minutes, I recommend checking that out first. It might provide some useful background information about and motivation for caring about how microphones fit into the whole “getting sound from the air into a computer” business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before getting into the specifics of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; microphones operate and the technical distinctions between different microphone technologies, let’s start by asking the question: what exactly does a microphone do? If you read my previous post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisweekinlearning.com/2018/09/08/signal-processing.html&quot;&gt;signal processing&lt;/a&gt; (last time I’ll link to that, promise), you’ll recall that microphones are tasked with changing a acoustic signal (air pressure) into an analogous electric signal (measured in voltage fluctuations). This process of converting energy from one form to another is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transducer&quot;&gt;transduction&lt;/a&gt;, meaning that microphones are a type of “transducer.” Our lives are full of transducers. Think of a mercury thermometer that turns the energy of air temperature into some kind of pressure that causes the liquid inside to rise and fall. Microphones do the same thing: they take the air pressure fluctuations created by the strumming of a guitar or the vibration of vocal cords and convert it into electrical energy which can be amplified, recorded, and later re-created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All microphones are transducers and are designed to accomplish this energy conversion task, but not all microphones do it in the same way. While there have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronics.howstuffworks.com/gadgets/audio-music/question309.htm&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; different microphone technologies developed throughout the (relatively) short history of audio recording, I’m going to focus on the two most popular types that are used today: &lt;strong&gt;dynamic&lt;/strong&gt; microphones and &lt;strong&gt;condenser&lt;/strong&gt; microphones. Neither microphone type is inherently superior to the other, each has its own set of benefits and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/malefit&quot;&gt;malefits&lt;/a&gt; which make it a better or worse choice in different recording contexts. I’ll discuss some of these more at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;dynamic-microphones&quot;&gt;Dynamic Microphones&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/microphone-types/Figure 1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I asked you to close your eyes and imagine a microphone, it’s likely that you would have conjured an image of the microphone depicted above, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shure.com/americas/products/microphones/SM/sm58-vocal-microphone&quot;&gt;Shure SM-58 Dynamic Vocal Microphone&lt;/a&gt;. The SM-58 was developed in 1966 and has been the world’s best-selling microphone ever since, favored by touring musicians due to its rugged construction, simplicity, and affordability. If you go ahead and Google your favorite band and look at concert photos, there’s a very good chance that the lead singer is holding one of these in their hand. The SM-58 is the prototypical example of a dynamic microphone. But let’s take a look now at what’s going on underneath its iconic spherical steel mesh grille.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/microphone-types/Figure 2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Diagram of the construction of a dynamic microphone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediacollege.com/audio/microphones/dynamic.html&quot;&gt;Image from Mediacollege.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next section is going to include some technical explanations that might seem off-putting to someone who has bad memories of their high school physics class. If you feel your eyes glazing over, just keep in mind what our energy conversion goal is: sound waves to electrical signal. Something inside the microphone has to react to the stream of changes in air pressure and somehow create electrical charge in the process, a process which kind of seems like magic. And what is usually responsible when some technical process seems like magic? That’s right: &lt;strong&gt;magnets.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diagram above depicts the internals of a dynamic microphone. The first part worth noting is the diaphragm. This is usually a very very thin piece of material that moves back and forth when it comes into contact with sound waves—think of the taut membrane stretched over a drum. The diaphragm interacts directly with the stream of sound waves, vibrating upon contact with them and thus converting the form of energy from acoustic to mechanical. But it’s not just the diaphragm which moves. The next part of the diagram, the coil, is attached directly to the diaphragm in dynamic microphones, and therefore moves back and forth as well. This movement in response to the incoming sound saves is where the name ‘dynamic’ comes from: things are actually moving around in there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the magnet comes in. You’ll notice in the diagram that the coil is surrounding a stationary magnet. For &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faraday%27s_law_of_induction&quot;&gt;reasons a little outside my realm of comprehension&lt;/a&gt;, when you move a metal coil inside of a magnetic field, electrical fluctuations are generated in the coil corresponding to the relative movement of the coil and the magnet. You might remember doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicalphysics.org/magnet-and-coil.html&quot;&gt;an experiment in a physics class&lt;/a&gt; which proves this. As the coil moves back and forth along the magnet, an electrical current is generated and sent down the wires attached to it, and &lt;em&gt;violà!&lt;/em&gt; We’ve gone from acoustic energy to electrical! Because of this interaction between the coil’s movement and the magnet, the operative principle that allows dynamic microphones to function is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electromagnetism&quot;&gt;electromagnetism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;condenser-microphones&quot;&gt;Condenser Microphones&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/microphone-types/Figure 3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever used a “shotgun” microphone, the kind that you might place on top of a video camera and point in the direction of the thing you are trying to record, then you have probably used a condenser microphone. The tiny lavalier microphones that you see clipped to peoples’ lapels during interviews? Also mostly condenser microphones. While there is not one single condenser microphone with the popularity of the Shure SM-58 that we looked at in the last section, they are no less widely used in the world of recording. While dynamic microphones rely on the magic of magnets to function as transducers, condenser microphones have a completely different strategy for converting acoustic energy into electrical energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/microphone-types/Figure 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Diagram of the construction of a condenser microphone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediacollege.com/audio/microphones/condenser.html&quot;&gt;Image from Mediacollege.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a condenser microphone, there is no magnet, but there must be a power source. Depending on the microphone, this can either be provided by a battery inside the microphone or it can be sent to the microphone from the device that it is plugged into using a standard called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_power&quot;&gt;phantom power&lt;/a&gt;. Why does there need to be a power source? Let’s take a closer look at the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember learning in high school physics class that electrons will flow from areas of positive charge to areas of negative charge? Well, that’s basically how condenser microphones work. In fact, “condenser” is just an older word for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capacitor&quot;&gt;“capacitor”&lt;/a&gt;, a concept with which you may be more familiar. A capacitor is an electronic component that can store an electric charge, kind of like a battery, &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronics.howstuffworks.com/capacitor.htm&quot;&gt;but different in some essential ways&lt;/a&gt;. While capacitors were traditionally used in electronics to hold a charge and then discharge it very quickly, like in the flash on your camera, some clever engineers figured out that they could also be used as sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When hooked up to a battery or other power source, the polarized front and back plates in the diagram above create a capacitor whose capacitance is controlled by the distance between the plates. The front plate serves as the diaphragm, free to move as it interacts with incoming sound waves, causing the capacitance to change as the air pressure around it does. A clever circuit design involving a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resistors&quot;&gt;resistor&lt;/a&gt; (not pictured in the diagram above) allows this change in capacitance to be measured as a change in electrical potential energy, in volts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the diaphragm in a condenser microphone isn’t attached to a (relatively) heavy metal coil, it is able to respond to much finer changes in pressure than most dynamic microphones, making it more suited to capturing high frequency sounds. The main downside to condenser microphones is the need for an external power supply, although some variations on the condenser microphone, known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neumann.com/homestudio/en/what-is-the-difference-between-electret-condenser-and-true-condenser-microphones&quot;&gt;Electret condenser&lt;/a&gt;, do not require this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;so-which-is-better&quot;&gt;So which is better?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their technical differences in how they achieve this goal, both dynamic and condenser microphones are transducers, converting acoustic energy to electrical signal. Neither technology is inherently better than the other, but as I mentioned earlier, there are certain use-cases that favor one method of transduction over the other. Dynamic microphones are a favorite among stage musicians, live concert engineers, and people who need to record really loud sounds because of their comparable durability and ability to function without external power. Field reporters, film studios, and nature recorders might prefer condenser microphones because of their very accurate frequency responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no clear answer to the question of which microphone is the best overall, and even for each situation, it can be muddy, a lot of it comes down to taste, preference, budget, and circumstance. Hopefully you are now inspired to go and experiment with the two types, listening for the differences in sound created by the two different transduction technologies. If you aren’t someone that works with microphones and sound (as you probably aren’t), I hope that from now on, when you are watching the news, at a concert, or listening to music, you think about the engineering marvels at work in bringing that sound from its source to your ears.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jackson Bierfeldt</name></author><summary type="html">In this post, I set out to explain two basic types of microphones and how they work. This post is in some ways a successor to my previous post about signal processing and flow; if you didn’t read that one already, and you have a spare few minutes, I recommend checking that out first. It might provide some useful background information about and motivation for caring about how microphones fit into the whole “getting sound from the air into a computer” business.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/microphone-types.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Off-White (Not the Color)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/11/off-white.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Off-White (Not the Color)" /><published>2018-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/11/off-white</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/11/off-white.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine the scene: it’s a crisp fall night, and you’re inside the impossibly European confines of a spacious, &lt;em&gt;Altbau&lt;/em&gt; apartment in Linz, Austria. You’ve arrived at the party and the visual dissonance takes a minute to digest – clean, elegant décor is juxtaposed against the streetwear-clad DJs and electronic music enthusiasts who frequent Linz’s most beloved dive bars. You’ve caught the party on an upswing; something on vinyl spins in the background and glasses are filled and refilled with open bottles on the kitchen island. You can’t help but notice that your prissy, velvet shirt doesn’t quite fit with the blur of streetwear in the room — oversized, vintage Adidas, Fred Perry sweatshirts, and sleek, Acne Studios jewelry. Skinny Russian cigarettes dangle between fingers, and new-wave fanny packs, draped across the chest, are most likely stuffed with rolling papers and tobacco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current heartbeat of fashion is arguably luxury streetwear. Even tucked away in Austrian obscurity, not only is the aesthetic sustained, but one designer and his brand dominate the discussion: Virgil Abloh, and his ever-controversial label Off-White. I didn’t spot a single Off-White piece in the room, and yet, the brand topping Q3 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyst.com/the-lyst-index/2018/q3/&quot;&gt;Lyst’s 2018 quarterly index&lt;/a&gt; was energetically discussed with sour disdain, ambivalence, and plain dislike. To this Austrian sub-crowd, Off-White is overhyped, oversimplified, and overpriced. Equipped with only basic knowledge of the brand (and anticipating Off-White/Virgil recurring as a conversation topic), I was inspired to learn all I could about Off-White: the brand that sells through $1,000 sweatshirts and creates sneakers that resell at 450% above retail (think $800+ Nikes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/off-white/Figure 1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off-White’s controversy lies mainly in the aesthetic it propagates. Virgil’s Milan-based brand is easily recognizable by its graphic, yet minimalist visual concept. Virgil stamps his Off-White pieces with to-the-point, anodyne words and phrases. Most text is written in Helvetica typeface, almost always in quotation marks: shoelaces with “Shoelaces” printed on them or a scarf with “Scarf” in bold, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vogue.com/article/intarsia-fashion-word-of-the-day&quot;&gt;intarsia&lt;/a&gt; letters. A black, leather tote with “Sculpture” in white letters sells for over $1,000, and a pair of leather, cowboy-inspired boots labeled “For Walking” retails for $2,290. All of these items can be found on the Off-White website, aptly labelled “website.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/off-white/Figure 2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/off-white/Figure 3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sky-high prices, in regard to any brand, almost ask for a scoff or an upturned nose. However, my learning endeavor revealed how misaligned my preconceptions were with the mind behind Off-White. I used to live firmly in the ‘ambivalent’ camp regarding Virgil and Off-White — streetwear wasn’t super relevant to my sartorial choices, and luxury wasn’t (and honestly still isn’t) financially accessible.
To Virgil Abloh, “you can use typography and wording to completely change the perception of a thing without changing anything about it. If I take a men’s sweatshirt and write ‘woman’ on its back, that’s art.” To him, the division between art and fashion doesn’t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; have to exist. This philosophy drives his designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virgil makes very deliberate design choices. Helvetica was not random, but chosen because it references the mid-century aesthetic exemplified by one of Virgil’s earliest influences at the Illinois Institute of Technology, where he earned his Master of Architecture. Virgil studied the work of German-American architect Mies van der Rohe, who directed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theartstory.org/movement-bauhaus.htm&quot;&gt;Bauhaus movement&lt;/a&gt; just before modernist art was banned by the Nazis. Mies left Germany shortly thereafter, and moved to Chicago to head the architecture department at IIT. Nowadays, Helvetica can be considered a masterpiece of the twentieth century. It is an ubiquitous font that disappears in plain sight – for example, the words you are reading right now are being displayed in Helvetica. Developed in 1957, it is the font “used in the logos of American Apparel, General Motors, Panasonic and BMW, as well as on federal income tax forms and the insides of NASA’s space shuttle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virgil’s trademark quotation marks are both a design refrain and a pointed use of punctuation, meant to invoke a specific mood and mindset. Quotations create instability, as empirical facts are never in quotations. Furthermore, quotations proposition the reader to question the information between the speech marks. Virgil explains this concept in an interview with the Berlin-based magazine &lt;em&gt;O32c&lt;/em&gt;, a publication that contextualizes fashion within a wider cultural setting. Journalist Thom Bettridge recalled in the piece: “quotation marks are one of the many tools that Abloh uses to operate in a mode of ironic detachment… Abloh rejects the who-did-it-first mentality of previous generations in favor of the copy-paste logic of the Internet and its inhabitants. His new order is protected by a fortress of irony.” This is how Virgil asks the reader to consider the difference between a handbag and a piece art – is there really a difference?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virgil’s Off-White designs provide a fresh angle on the complicated relationship between fashion and art, though this conversation isn’t entirely new. Dadaism pioneer Marcel Duchamp famously questioned fundamental assumptions about art with his concept of the Readymade. By taking everyday objects (most notably, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks/duchamp-fountain-t07573&quot;&gt;a urinal&lt;/a&gt;) and presenting them as art, Duchamp asked us to consider: What constitutes art? What can be art? Does art have to be beautiful? In a way, Virgil’s Off-White is a second renaissance of this line of questioning. Virgil’s conceptions of what is good, beautiful, and important once again blur our understanding of art and fashion as separate entities. Furthermore, Virgil seems to define beauty in part by modern metrics such as impact and relevance. In 2018, perceptions of importance and number of hashtag mentions per hour do matter for brands – ask any one of the 5.4 million Instagram followers he has garnered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/off-white/Figure 4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image 4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the industry, Virgil Abloh is viewed as extremely media-literate, meticulous, and hard-working. In addition to Off-White, Virgil was recently appointed as the artistic director for Louis Vuitton menswear, and is the first Black man to hold this position in Vuitton’s 164-year history. He is also the first true Midwesterner in the position – he currently lives in Lincoln Park with his wife and two kids, but was born and raised in Rockford, Illinois to Ghanaian parents.
Without any base information on Off-White or Virgil Abloh, a superficial glance at the brand might make Virgil and his designs seem gimmicky. This take would reduce Off-White to what you might have already concluded about fashion as a whole – it is thoughtless and vapid.&lt;br /&gt;
Fashion will always be subjective, but Virgil Abloh is objectively a respected fixture in the industry. Regardless of your opinion on Virgil and Off-White, customers and counterparts alike acknowledge his influence and innovation. Moreover, they acknowledge that the “branded sensationalism” he has created cannot be reduced to empty buzz. Virgil aims to provoke from a genuine place of societal reflection, using fashion as a vehicle. Virgil’s Off-White brings multiple fields into a fruitful discussion, and Off-White’s ability to inspire meaningful conversation is probably why Virgil Abloh stands among figures like Justin Trudeau, Meghan Markle, and Oprah on Time’s 2018 100 Most Influential People in the World list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.complex.com/style/2018/10/off-white-is-now-the-most-popular-fashion-brand-according-to-report&quot;&gt;https://www.complex.com/style/2018/10/off-white-is-now-the-most-popular-fashion-brand-according-to-report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanityfair.com/style/2018/08/virgil-abloh-louis-vuitton-designer-director&quot;&gt;https://www.vanityfair.com/style/2018/08/virgil-abloh-louis-vuitton-designer-director&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessoffashion.com/articles/fashion-show-review/branded-sensationalism-at-off-white&quot;&gt;https://www.businessoffashion.com/articles/fashion-show-review/branded-sensationalism-at-off-white&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.highsnobiety.com/2017/08/30/virgil-abloh-off-white-quotation-marks/&quot;&gt;https://www.highsnobiety.com/2017/08/30/virgil-abloh-off-white-quotation-marks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vogue.com/article/virgil-abloh-mens-artistic-director-louis-vuitton-spring-2019-chicago&quot;&gt;https://www.vogue.com/article/virgil-abloh-mens-artistic-director-louis-vuitton-spring-2019-chicago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moma.org/learn/moma_learning/themes/dada/marcel-duchamp-and-the-readymade/&quot;&gt;https://www.moma.org/learn/moma_learning/themes/dada/marcel-duchamp-and-the-readymade/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Other Contributors</name></author><summary type="html">Imagine the scene: it’s a crisp fall night, and you’re inside the impossibly European confines of a spacious, Altbau apartment in Linz, Austria. You’ve arrived at the party and the visual dissonance takes a minute to digest – clean, elegant décor is juxtaposed against the streetwear-clad DJs and electronic music enthusiasts who frequent Linz’s most beloved dive bars. You’ve caught the party on an upswing; something on vinyl spins in the background and glasses are filled and refilled with open bottles on the kitchen island. You can’t help but notice that your prissy, velvet shirt doesn’t quite fit with the blur of streetwear in the room — oversized, vintage Adidas, Fred Perry sweatshirts, and sleek, Acne Studios jewelry. Skinny Russian cigarettes dangle between fingers, and new-wave fanny packs, draped across the chest, are most likely stuffed with rolling papers and tobacco.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/off-white.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gravity Model and Traffic Flow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/04/gravity-model-and-traffic-flow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gravity Model and Traffic Flow" /><published>2018-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/04/gravity-model-and-traffic-flow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/04/gravity-model-and-traffic-flow.html">&lt;p&gt;This week’s post is written with inspiration from my young and bright cousin, Karston Ryan. A couple of weeks ago I asked him if he would like to write a post on our TWIL page here, and he graciously declined my offer. However, he mentioned that he was curious about something called a gravity model. Luckily, I have no prior knowledge of this topic and it sounds intriguing, so hopefully you readers out there and myself will learn something new together as I write this post. This one’s for you, cuz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick, preliminary Google search of the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_model_of_migration&quot;&gt;gravity model&lt;/a&gt;” yields insight into its application in the social sciences. In essence, gravity models predict relationships between people, places, and goods in terms of Newton’s law of gravity: particles attract each other with a force directly related to the product of their masses and indirectly related to the square of the distance between their centers. There are many, many types of gravity models. Isard’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_model_of_trade&quot;&gt;gravity model of trade&lt;/a&gt;, Ravenstein’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_model_of_migration&quot;&gt;gravity model of migration&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;tfresource.org/Category:Spatial_interaction_models&quot;&gt;gravity model of spatial interaction&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zelinsky_Model&quot;&gt;Zelinsky model&lt;/a&gt;, and so on. Flipping through these, I found one specific application of the gravity model that perhaps most, if not, all of us can relate to: traffic flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic flow is dependent on the gravity model of migration, where the degree of interaction between two places is dependent on the location of the place and its importance. Much like particles in a Newtonian model, if a city with a large degree of “importance”—i.e. population, or “mass”, commerce, etc …—is located close enough to another city of equal importance, the degree of migration will increase between them. If the locations are farther apart, the degree of migration will decrease. I think a map of the “Texas Triangle” is a good example for applying this model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/gravity-flow/Picture 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between Dallas and Austin, a 2-4 hour drive depending on traffic, the populations are similar: about 1 million in each city. This drive is typically very smooth and uneventful with the occasional light traffic, depending on the day, time and weather. A gravity model would predict a large degree of migration between the cities over the span of, say, five years and as such the volume of traffic would be substantial. The same can be said of any two or three cities within the triangle, since they are heavily populated and within 5 hours driving of one another. If we narrow our scope to smaller, population-heavy pockets within the Dallas city limits, the nature of traffic flow is more applicable to the gravity model.
My home city, Desoto, TX, is located within Dallas county and has a population of 53, 568 (2017). I frequently drive between my home and Richardson, TX with a population of 116,783 (2017). The distance between the cities is 29.5 miles. On average, it takes me about an hour to an hour and a half to arrive in Richardson in the morning on a weekday, and the same amount of time to return home on a weekday in the evening. Of course, we can explain away these travel times as due to rush hour and highway construction and so on, but traffic flow and the gravity model include some other interesting things to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic flow is determined by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-phase_traffic_theory#The_%22synchronized_flow%22_phase_%5BS%5D&quot;&gt;three-phase traffic theory&lt;/a&gt; (developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boris_Kerner&quot;&gt;Boris Kerner&lt;/a&gt; in ’96) which includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free flow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synchronized flow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wide moving jam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My commute includes a minimal amount of “free flow”, which is the relationship between the number of vehicles over time and the vehicle density over distance. If there were very few traveling vehicles alongside of me over my 30 mile drive, then I would have a smooth, stress-free trip to Richardson. Unfortunately, Richardson lies on the other side of Dallas and the highways mix together in the middle to bring all the commuters at once into Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/gravity-flow/Picture 2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skipping the “synchronized flow” for a second, my commute is almost entirely that of a “wide moving jam.” Traffic of this nature moves upstream through bottlenecks upon the highway. This phenomena is known as such because, despite the bottlenecks, the traffic jam will make an attempt to continue through the bottleneck at the same velocity at which it entered, so the jam as one “wide moving” unit “jammed” into a small hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Synchronized flow” can be described as a continuous flow of traffic with no stopping, and this is interesting because it demonstrates a strange tendency for a large number of individuals in different vehicles, moving to different places, to unconsciously act in synchrony due to the nature of their surroundings. During this flow, the vehicle speeds tend to synchronize across multiple lanes of traffic and within each lane of traffic. This explains why you’ve sat in a “wide moving jam”, coasting along together with the lady in the lane over who has been jamming to Beyonce for the last 15 mins, and then suddenly, it seems as if the traffic disappears and everyone resumes their normal travel speeds. Despite the bottleneck having been conquered, the cars on the highway were still moving in synchrony until the farther cars ahead sped forward once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the gravity model, well, a lot of people travel across the highways in Dallas to reach population centers outside of Dallas for work or school. A map of Dallas reveals this nature of the commute, as downtown Dallas is located at the hub of a wheel of interconnected highways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/gravity-flow/Picture 3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Image 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us that travel to work or school daily, I think the gravity model is an interesting application to commuting and can be applied between locations of shorter distances and smaller populations with as well. You might even think of the gravity model at play between your living room and the kitchen during Thanksgiving. I hope the traffic in the hallway is free and uncongested. 😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Mathis</name></author><summary type="html">This week’s post is written with inspiration from my young and bright cousin, Karston Ryan. A couple of weeks ago I asked him if he would like to write a post on our TWIL page here, and he graciously declined my offer. However, he mentioned that he was curious about something called a gravity model. Luckily, I have no prior knowledge of this topic and it sounds intriguing, so hopefully you readers out there and myself will learn something new together as I write this post. This one’s for you, cuz.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/gravity-flow.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Restoration (Part 1/2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/21/architectural-concepts-restoration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restoration (Part 1/2)" /><published>2018-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/21/architectural-concepts-restoration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/21/architectural-concepts-restoration.html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I’d like to share the first in a two-part series, in which I talk through some architectural examples of two concepts—restoration and obsolescence—that have been floating around in some of the media I’ve been consuming recently. I’m going to start with restoration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A side-note: part of the reason I’m interested in these two ideas together is because of &lt;em&gt;The Future of Nostalgia&lt;/em&gt;, a book I read a little bit of earlier this year. The author writes a little about how nostalgia, at first considered quite a serious disease, was cured in two different, opposite ways. During the 18th century, when Swiss soldiers serving abroad in France were beset by nostalgia, it was a sickness induced by “rustic mothers’ soups, thick village milk and the folk melodies of Alpine valleys[!]” — the only cure was to send them home. (These afflictions were deeply stereotypical, apparently; Scottish soldiers had a similar reaction to the sound of bagpipes.) But when French soldiers suffered from nostalgic sickness during the French Revolution, one doctor &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=R26XcPLrEAAC&amp;amp;pg=PA23&amp;amp;lpg=PA23&amp;amp;dq=jourdan+le+cointe+nostalgia&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=XMdyGN9ZxM&amp;amp;sig=l_piCnxgNbjQQhmgSEgegxDQ8hE&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiEr4etkpTeAhUE5YMKHWDjCzEQ6AEwCXoECAkQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=jourdan%20le%20cointe%20nostalgia&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;wrote that&lt;/a&gt; “nostalgia can be defeated by inciting pain or terror. One should tell the nostalgic soldier that ‘a red-hot iron applied to his abdomen’ will cure him immediately.” These are the two remedies for nostalgia, then: a return to the past, or a violence inspired by revolution.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll focus on Giovanni Piranesi and his famous engravings of ancient Rome. Piranesi was an 18th-century Italian artist who was born and lived most of his life in poverty. Though from Venice, he moved to Rome at age seventeen, persuaded at least in part by a girl he was in love with, who, &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/piranesi00samu/page/n11&quot;&gt;in the words&lt;/a&gt; of one of Piranesi’s biographers, “spoke to him of Rome, of Rome with its infinite Art treasures.” (She later “threw him over,” in the words of the same biographer, and married the Count of Amalfi.) There, he studied architecture and etching. When he was twenty, he tried to murder one of his masters who had refused to teach him the secret of using aqua fortis—nitric acid—to make engravings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that gives at least some sense of the kind of personality we’re dealing with. (If not, our friend the biographer provides a helpful list of descriptors: “jealous,” “perhaps vain to a high degree,” “perpetually involved in some sort of dispute.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1756, Piranesi published &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/gri_33125010859979/page/n15&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Antichità Romane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a four-volume book of etchings. The volumes are an artistic, archaeological exploration of Ancient Rome, with detailed renderings of remaining ruins alongside theorizing about what the original might have looked like. Take, for instance, this work, which describes the mausoleum of Caecilia Mettela, daughter-in-law of Marcus Crassus, who formed part of the First Triumvirate alongside Julius Caesar. For all its beauty and complexity, Piranesi’s work is basically a modern look at antiquity (e.g., you can see rubble and foliage in a few of the drawings).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/architectural-restoration/figure1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pictures in the Antichità Romane were mostly attempts to do archaeology, focusing on the ancient structures by themselves; Piranesi would later publish &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/McGillLibrary-rbsc_piranesi-battista_1720-1778_vedute-di-roma-16608/page/n21&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vedute di Roma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a more artistic work depicting Roman ruins in their modern context. Below is his drawing of the atrium of the portico of Octavia, an old structure restored by Augustus, the first emperor of Rome. Piranesi’s 18th-century drawing places the portico in an 18th-century context: there is (again) the stray plant growth, fish market stalls running along the street outside, women dressed in wide Mantua gowns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/architectural-restoration/figure2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these series, the &lt;em&gt;Antichità&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Vedute&lt;/em&gt;, are interesting and beautiful in their own right, but the most fascinating work that Piranesi created, in my opinion, was the &lt;em&gt;Campius Martius antiquade Urbis&lt;/em&gt; from 1762. Ostensibly, this volume of etchings sets out to reconstruct the Campo Marzio, a part of Ancient Rome sandwiched between the river Tiber and the walls of the city proper. In reality, it’s a strange mixture of history, fiction, and semi-fiction blended together. Let me begin with a couple of plates from the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/architectural-restoration/figure3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/architectural-restoration/figure4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Neither of these tiny reproductions do the full-scale versions justice; if you have a chance, go and look at them in detail here and here.) Anyway, these two plates give a good sense of the project. In the top one, “Scenographia Campi Martii”, there’s a horseshoe-shaped track with a hard-to-discern structure in the middle of it. According to architect &lt;a href=&quot;http://booksc.xyz/book/26724816/3b06bd&quot;&gt;Stanley Allen&lt;/a&gt;, those are the only modern-day remains of the Stadium of Domitian. (“Rome’s first permanent venue for competitive athletics,” says Wikipedia!) But Allen also points out that the suggestion that the stadium, when Piranesi drew it around 1760, just stood by itself on an arid, marshy plain is a lie, intentionally leaving out the churches and houses had been built over its remains during the medieval era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So part of what Piranesi does is remove all the interceding history between himself and the past, and then nevertheless represent the stadium as a historical ruin, something that’s been worn down by time and neglect. He also places the actual and imaginary next to each other. The second plate above is “Ichnographia Campi Martii Antiquae Urbis”; at first glance, it just looks like a blueprint for a city. But if we zoom in a little bit…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/architectural-restoration/figure5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is from the bottom right corner of the bigger plate, if you’re following along at home.) I want to talk about two structures here. The first is the Horti Valeriani, which is notable for a couple of reasons. It belonged to the family of the husband of Melania the Younger, a notably ascetic saint who gave large chunks of her inherited wealth. (No word on whether she convinced her husband’s family to do anything with the Horti Valeriani.) The second is that it was plundered by the Visigoths the first time they sacked Rome. Anyway, it’s a real, once-extant historical building.
Then there’s the Porticus Neronianae immediately to the northwest. That’s a completely fictitious building, which doesn’t and never existed. It’s the same across the map — real buildings mingle with fake ones, as well as real buildings relocated from their original spots, placed somewhere else on the map according to whatever plan Piranesi had in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you’d like to explore Piranesi’s work further, I’d recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quondam.com/&quot;&gt;Quondam&lt;/a&gt;, a bizarre, half-conspiratorial project from architect Stephen Lauf that speculates about the Campo Marzio project in great, frenetically hyperlinked detail. For example, the description of the Porticus Neronianae runs as follows: “the shape of a large cross within a circle (a composition, coincidentally, that follows the circle/square juncture pattern similar to the Timepiece gauge of the theory of chronosomatics.)” I’m not quite sure what this means; a quick Google search for “chronosomatics” turns up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quondam.com/33/3392c.htm&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:RmPrF9gLSBIJ:www.quondam.com/46/4699c.htm+&amp;amp;cd=4&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=us&quot;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt;, some only cached, to Quondam, which suggest that it’s Lauf’s own theory, birthed in 1981 when he was “contemplating the possible meaning of a 15th century Annunciation painting that hangs in The National Gallery.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next month: obsolescence!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christian Belanger</name></author><summary type="html">This week, I’d like to share the first in a two-part series, in which I talk through some architectural examples of two concepts—restoration and obsolescence—that have been floating around in some of the media I’ve been consuming recently. I’m going to start with restoration.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/architectural-restoration.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Japanese Writing System(s)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/14/japanese-writing-systems.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japanese Writing System(s)" /><published>2018-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/14/japanese-writing-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/14/japanese-writing-systems.html">&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, I decided that I wanted to begin learning a new language. I have been learning German for about 5 years at this point, and after years of classroom study and living abroad, I have reached a point where the amount of effort it requires to make even a small leap in practical knowledge is sometimes overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/japanese-writing/schraubmuttern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Schraubmuttern&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There is something not quite satisfying about finally learning all of the different words for various types of nuts and bolts.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed those earth-shattering “Aha!” moments that seem to happen all of the time in the early stages of learning a new language, so, I enrolled in a Japanese 101 class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was looking for in learning a new language was to learn a new writing system. Although I had to learn to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://proxy.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.maccampus.de%2FImages%2FVomleichterenWege.JPG&amp;amp;f=1&quot;&gt;Fraktur script&lt;/a&gt; to do research in German, I still found myself wanting to get away from the Latin alphabet. I was excited to learn, then, that the standard pedagogical method of teaching Japanese as a foreign language is to start with the writing system; before being taught to speak even a single word or sentence, I was given several workbooks to use in practicing the writing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern Japanese’s writing system is interesting in that it contains 3 sub-systems within it: &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; (ひらがな), &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; (カタカナ), and &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; (漢字). Note the visual difference between the three systems. &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; characters are simple and feature lots of rounded and curved lines, &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; characters are simple and look more jagged and square, and &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; look very complex. (If &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; characters look ‘Chinese’ to you, then you have good intuition; more on that later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/japanese-writing/comparison.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of Hiragana, Katakana, and Kanji&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although each sub-system has particular contexts in which it is preferred, modern Japanese is written using a mix of all three. If you look at the Japanese-language wikipedia page for &lt;a href=&quot;https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%82%B3%E3%83%BC%E3%83%92%E3%83%BC&quot;&gt;Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll see all three writing sub-systems present in the first paragraph, seamlessly perched right next to one another in a single sentence. Although I’ve yet to visit Japan, I’m told that standing on a single street corner, it’s easy to find examples of all three (plus Romaji, Japanese written with the Latin alphabet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/japanese-writing/onthestreet.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;On the Street&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Image from: &lt;a href=&quot;http://japanisch-lernen.info/japanische-schriftzeichen-Hiragana-Katakana-Kanji/&quot;&gt;japanisch-lernen.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin by taking a closer look at &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt;, which are actually very similar systems, despite their contrasting appearances. They are similar in that both of these sub-systems are so-called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syllabary&quot;&gt;syllabaries&lt;/a&gt;, systems of symbols which represent, that’s right, you guessed it, syllables. This system of writing contrasts with the Latin alphabet we use to write English, in which each symbol represents an individual sound. Before I get into what exactly a syllabary system looks like, let’s spend a moment talking about syllables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about syllables, we are talking about the units of speech that we use to organize sounds into segments. In English, each syllable has at its core a vowel sound which is surrounded on either side by consonant sounds. For instance, in the word ‘dragon,’ we count two syllables: dr&lt;strong&gt;ah&lt;/strong&gt;-g&lt;strong&gt;uh&lt;/strong&gt;n. If we imagine for a second that English used a syllabary for its written system, maybe we would write the word ‘dragon’ as follows: §£, where the § symbol represents dr&lt;strong&gt;ah&lt;/strong&gt; and £ symbol represents g&lt;strong&gt;uh&lt;/strong&gt;n. Instead, with the Latin alphabet, we use these six letters ‘d-r-a-g-o-n’ to represent the following six sounds: /d/-/ɹ/-/æ/-/g/-/ə/-/n/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As syllabaries, each &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; character represents one syllable of the spoken language. For example, the word ‘cat’ in Japanese is pronounced ‘neko’ and is comprised of two syllables: ne-ko. The standard way of writing ‘cat’ in Japanese is using &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt;, and the word looks like this: ねこ. (ね = ‘ne’ and こ = ‘ko.’) Each character represents one syllable and only one syllable. If you read the ね character, you know that it will always be pronounced as the ‘ne’ syllable, with no exceptions. Contrast this with the letter ‘a’ in English, which is pronounced differently in all of the following words: m&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;n, y&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;cht, c&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;ught, alph&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;bet. Compared to English, Japanese is a relatively simple language in terms of its &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/30/mouth-meat.html&quot;&gt;phonology&lt;/a&gt;, meaning the inventory of sounds it contains. While American English speakers have as many as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_phonology#Vowels&quot;&gt;15 distinct vowel sounds&lt;/a&gt; (depending on dialect), Japanese speakers have 5: /a/, /i/, /u/, /e/, /o/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; works in the same way. In fact, you could also write the word ‘cat’ using &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt;. Both of the two syllabic sub-systems contain 46 symbols, corresponding to the 46 commonly used syllables in the Japanese language. ‘Cat’ in &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; would look like this: ネコ. You probably wouldn’t often see ‘cat’ written with &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt;, though, because of the two different contexts in which the different sub-systems are used. We’ll discuss these contexts for &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; before moving on to the third sub-system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; is used to write some common native Japanese words (like ‘cat’), grammatical markings on words (think ‘-ing’ suffix in English), and for function words and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_particle&quot;&gt;particles&lt;/a&gt;. It appears to be the work horse of the language, the basic words and the grammatical glue that binds them together. It’s not flashy, doesn’t put on airs; it does its job and then sits back down. &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, has a glossier feel to it. It’s often described as the equivalent of the English &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt; because of its ability to stand out visually. It’s typically used with foreign loan words, company names, scientific and medical names, and things that are meant to be emphasized. For English speakers, a good analogy that I’ve seen mentioned to help understand the feeling of &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; is to think of all of the long Latin and Greek words which features ‘y’s, ’x’s, and ‘ph’s, letters that are not commonly found in simpler ‘english’ words (etymologically speaking). When we see a word like ‘hypophosphate,’ we are visually cued as to the origin of the word. Similar with &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; and foreign loan words like ‘coffee’ (コーヒー) which are almost always written in &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why two completely separate and redundant sets of symbols? The answer, as it always is when it comes to seemingly confusing or inefficient systems in language, is weird historical reasons. The specifics of why and how each sub-system developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://japanese.stackexchange.com/questions/4281/why-was-both-Katakana-and-Hiragana-created&quot;&gt;are debated&lt;/a&gt;, but without going too deep into detail about something which I am not at all qualified to speculate upon, it is sufficient to know that each system developed separately (although from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man%27y%C5%8Dgana&quot;&gt;common ancestor&lt;/a&gt;) and as some kind of simplification of the Chinese writing system, which was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sljfaq.org/afaq/originofkana.html&quot;&gt;introduced to Japan&lt;/a&gt; sometime in the first few centuries AD, and is still used today as the third sub-system: &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt;, despite its complexity, is a very important part of the Japanese writing system. Looking at a paragraph of Japanese text, it is very easy to pick out which characters are &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt;, due to their relative complexity, even for someone who has zero experience learning Japanese. Whereas the &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; systems are syllabaries, &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logogram&quot;&gt;logographic&lt;/a&gt; sub-system, similar to ancient Egyptian hieroglyphics, wherein each character represents a word or phrase. For instance, the following &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; means “fabulous mythical bird; imperial”: 鸞. That’s a lot of meaning to pack into a single character on the page. (But hopefully you can also imagine the headache presented to those learning the language, as each &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; must be individually learned and memorized, along with its pronunciation.) Although there is no definitive count of &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; in Japanese (ditto for Chinese), there are about 50,000 &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; recognized in Japan’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanji#Total_number_of_*Kanji*&quot;&gt;gold-standard dictionary&lt;/a&gt;. As someone hoping to learn the language, however, I take heart in the fact that only about two or three thousand (!) &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; are regularly used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why have three sub-systems, though? Doesn’t this seem overly complicated? You wouldn’t be the first person to point this out. Despite being an entirely separate and unrelated language to Chinese, both phonologically and grammatically, Japanese’s writing system is very influenced by that of the Chinese, which has been at various times a sort of nationalistic sore-spot. As I mentioned before, even &lt;em&gt;Hiragana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Katakana&lt;/em&gt; are based on simplified Chinese characters. There have been various calls over time to change the Japanese writing system to move away from its reliance on the complicated &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; system, and although the system has been reformed and standardized over time, major efforts to completely move away from the Chinese system have proved unsuccessful, at least in Japan. In an successful attempt to improve literacy of the lower class, a 15th century Korean king created a syllabic writing system called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hangul#Creation&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hangul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which replaced the Chinese writing system that was used up until that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand here at the base of the language-learning mountain, gazing up at the thousands of arbitrary and complicated &lt;em&gt;Kanji&lt;/em&gt; characters, I’ll keep my fingers crossed for similar changes to Japanese writing system, but it doesn’t seem likely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jackson Bierfeldt</name></author><summary type="html">A couple months ago, I decided that I wanted to begin learning a new language. I have been learning German for about 5 years at this point, and after years of classroom study and living abroad, I have reached a point where the amount of effort it requires to make even a small leap in practical knowledge is sometimes overwhelming.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/japanese-writing-systems.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What the Hexus is Ecosystem Nexus?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/07/ecology-nexus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What the Hexus is Ecosystem Nexus?" /><published>2018-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/07/ecology-nexus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/07/ecology-nexus.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been writing case summaries of Supreme Court decisions for a legal education startup. One of the cases I wrote about this past week is &lt;em&gt;Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife&lt;/em&gt; (1992), which concerns an amendment to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA). The ESA lays out guidelines for what qualifies as a threatened or endangered species, and requires the Secretary of the Interior to use those guidelines to make a list of threatened or endangered species and each species’ critical habitat. Section 7((a)(2)) of the ESA requires federal agencies to consult with the Secretary of the Interior to ensure that any actions the Secretary authorizes will not threaten or harm endangered species or natural habitats. The amendment at issue in &lt;em&gt;Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife&lt;/em&gt; eliminated the requirement that agencies funding overseas projects consult the Secretary to evaluate the potential impact of proposed projects on endangered species. After Congress passed the amendment in 1986, Defenders of Wildlife and several other environmental organizations sued then-Secretary of the Interior Manuel Lujan, Jr. under the claim that the amendment unlawfully established a geographic limit to the Endangered Species Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this case, the Supreme Court had on many occasions reasserted the doctrine of federal justiciability originally established in Article III of the Constitution. Article III lays out parameters for the kinds of disputes that can be resolved in federal court; for a plaintiff to have the standing to bring their case to federal court, they must have suffered an “injury in fact” (meaning some discernible direct injury, though the phrase’s exact meaning is still debated), which can be traced to the action over which the plaintiff is suing, which could at least be somewhat resolved by a court ruling in favor of the plaintiff. (As a small aside, the whole concept of an individual somehow not having the ‘standing’ to file a lawsuit against another person/entity is still kind of insane to me. If you, too, are baffled, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/standing-to-sue&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to gently dip your toes into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://law.justia.com/constitution/us/article-3/20-substantial-interest-standing.html&quot;&gt;‘standing to sue’ ocean&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re feeling adventurous and want to maybe dip a whole foot in, take a peak at Justice Scalia’s opinion for the majority in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/504/555#writing-USSC_CR_0504_0555_ZO&quot;&gt;this case&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, Defenders of Wildlife claimed that the amendment would lead to the United States funding activities abroad that would threaten endangered species and environments in which Defenders of Wildlife employees work and conduct research. Defenders of Wildlife therefore asserted its standing to sue on behalf of its employees under the theory of “ecosystem nexus”. According to the theory of ecosystem nexus, any individual who uses part of an ecosystem affected by government-funded activity has the standing to sue the government for damaging that individual’s ability to use that part of the ecosystem. To me, this seemed perhaps the only way lawsuits over environmental issues could be brought on a large scale, but also way too broad to be accepted in federal court. In his 1973 book &lt;em&gt;Should Trees Have Standing? Toward Legal Rights for Natural Objects&lt;/em&gt;, Christopher Stone proposes another hook attorneys could use to file lawsuits over environmental issues. Stone argues that the environment should be legally able to have an attorney file a lawsuit on its behalf in the same way that a legal guardian does for children, people with certain disabilities, and others who are not considered able to make legal decisions for themselves. Stone’s proposal has gained even less traction in mainstream legal thought than ecosystem nexus, but is nonetheless at least worth playing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ecosystem nexus argument made its debut in &lt;em&gt;Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife&lt;/em&gt;, after a similar argument was used in the case &lt;em&gt;Lujan v National Wildlife Federation&lt;/em&gt; (1990). In that case, the National Wildlife Federation argued that individuals who use land near some other piece of land that is being affected by a group’s actions have the standing to sue that group over their actions. This argument, later referred to as “geographical nexus”, at first glance might appear identical to ecological nexus; however, by shifting from a geographical effects to ecological effects, Defenders of Wildlife thought it could establish a much more discernible “injury in fact”. If the government damages a piece of land and that damage affects the people who live next door, that injury is quite different than if the government damages an ecosystem. Damage to an ecosystem reverberates far beyond one neighbor and can cause significant damage both to the environment and the individuals working with any component of that ecosystem. The Supreme Court actually said as much in its ruling on &lt;em&gt;Japan Whaling Assn v American Cetacean Society&lt;/em&gt; (1986), in which Justice White wrote for the majority that the practice of whaling in one part of the world is an injury in fact to anyone wishing to study or observe whales in any other part of the world. Justices Kennedy, Stevens, Blackmun, and O’Connor cited the ruling in &lt;em&gt;Japan Whaling Assn v American Cetacean Society&lt;/em&gt; to argue that ecosystem nexus theory provided standing in &lt;em&gt;Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife&lt;/em&gt; and the injuries suffered did indeed constitute injuries in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority, however, ended up rejecting the theory of ecosystem nexus with a 6-3 ruling in favor of Lujan. The majority determined that the plaintiffs had shown no injury in fact caused to them by the amendment, and therefore Defenders of Wildlife lacked the standing to sue. Justice Scalia’s majority opinion in this case is well-known for its discussion of standing in general, but it is worth noting his treatment of ecosystem nexus specifically, as well as nexus theories in overall. Justice Scalia wrote that ecosystem nexus aimed to give standing to sue to “persons who use portions of an ecosystem not perceptibly affected by the unlawful action [of governments or groups]”. He argued that harm felt by one part of a system from damage done to another part is not the same as an injury in fact. Nexus theories in his view therefore lacked sufficient evidence of direct injury to provide standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the reason ecosystem nexus at first seemed so bizarre to me is because we now know the long-lasting ripple effects of past government and industry actions, and it’s somewhat unfathomable to me that a court could deem damage to an ecosystem not an injury in fact to those who are part of it. So far, I haven’t found any recent cases in which ecosystem nexus was used to argue standing to sue, but it is possible that the prevailing view of ecosystem nexus theory could change in the near future as people search to hold someone accountable for the injuries suffered from climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stus.com/stus-cartoon.php?name=Lujan+v.+Defenders+of+Wildlife&amp;amp;cartoon=con0101&quot;&gt;Cartoon by Stu’s Views&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oyez.org/cases/1991/90-1424&quot;&gt;https://www.oyez.org/cases/1991/90-1424&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/504/555/#tab-opinion-1959033&quot;&gt;https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/504/555/#tab-opinion-1959033&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lujan_v._Defenders_of_Wildlife&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lujan_v._Defenders_of_Wildlife&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://environs.law.ucdavis.edu/volumes/18/2/articles/sullivan.pdf&quot;&gt;https://environs.law.ucdavis.edu/volumes/18/2/articles/sullivan.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lawreview.vermontlaw.edu/staff-note-lujan-v-defenders-of-wildlife-can-environmental-litigants-regain-ground-to-stand-on-using-the-ecosystem-nexus-test-for-causation-redressibility/&quot;&gt;https://lawreview.vermontlaw.edu/staff-note-lujan-v-defenders-of-wildlife-can-environmental-litigants-regain-ground-to-stand-on-using-the-ecosystem-nexus-test-for-causation-redressibility/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/high-seas&quot;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/topic/high-seas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Other Contributors</name></author><summary type="html">Recently I’ve been writing case summaries of Supreme Court decisions for a legal education startup. One of the cases I wrote about this past week is Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife (1992), which concerns an amendment to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA). The ESA lays out guidelines for what qualifies as a threatened or endangered species, and requires the Secretary of the Interior to use those guidelines to make a list of threatened or endangered species and each species’ critical habitat. Section 7((a)(2)) of the ESA requires federal agencies to consult with the Secretary of the Interior to ensure that any actions the Secretary authorizes will not threaten or harm endangered species or natural habitats. The amendment at issue in Lujan v Defenders of Wildlife eliminated the requirement that agencies funding overseas projects consult the Secretary to evaluate the potential impact of proposed projects on endangered species. After Congress passed the amendment in 1986, Defenders of Wildlife and several other environmental organizations sued then-Secretary of the Interior Manuel Lujan, Jr. under the claim that the amendment unlawfully established a geographic limit to the Endangered Species Act.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/ecology-nexus.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You’ve Got Rocks in Your Ear, Old Man?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/30/youve-got-rocks-in-your-ears-old-man.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You’ve Got Rocks in Your Ear, Old Man?" /><published>2018-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/30/youve-got-rocks-in-your-ears-old-man</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/30/youve-got-rocks-in-your-ears-old-man.html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever seen someone stumbling through the street, you may have thought to yourself, “this person’s off their rocker!” The origin of the phrase is unclear, but perhaps I could provide some insight through a different type of “rock”. It’s hard to believe that the survival of every human depends on rocks—the rocks in your inner ear. Without these rocks, it would be really hard to wake up in the morning and brush your teeth for work (which for some, may be a blessing in disguise). If someone crashed into your car, and the rocks in your ear were knocked loose, you would most definitely be dazed and confused. In general, it would be quite uncomfortable attempting to discern the location of your body or your surroundings or really anything at all. These almighty, glorious and life-saving rocks, called otoconia, live in the inner ear of all humans and fortunately, they allow us to understand that our head is in motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otoconia look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they’re located here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is located in there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But way deeper. Closer to your brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no exaggeration that otoconia are actually rocks. Composed of calcium carbonate—the same material found in coral reefs—these “ear stones” rest upon a gelatinous membrane and rub against “hairs” during any tilting motion of the head. The stones closely resemble crystals in their shape and size, and under electron microscopy, appear to be scattered chaotically along the otolithic membrane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The top images depict the otolithic membrane of the toad Bufo bufo. The bottom images show the same membrane but of the gecko Teratoscincus scuncus.
Although these images are taken from amphibians, the otoconia in humans are not dissimilar in their arrangement. Of course, you can even see some variation in crystal size between the images, but the main takeaway is that the arrangement appears chaotic and rock-like.
Images copied from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Evolution-of-Otolithic-Membrane.-Structure-of-in-Lychakov/c4d74b747ca282a31ff5f1302aeb2607f92f3384/figure/6&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the otolithic membrane functions to keep the otoconia in place during tilting motion. Just below the membrane lies a layer of “hair cells”, and when the head tilts or accelerates, the stones shear across the tops of these hair cells, sending a rush of potassium ions into the cell. The slight electrical charge on potassium ions functions as a &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/09/08/signal-processing.html&quot;&gt;signal&lt;/a&gt; and is relayed to the brain to be encoded as backward/forward tilt (a.k.a pitch) or acceleration/deceleration.  Much like an airplane’s flight control system or the &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/09/11/bug-nuisances.html&quot;&gt;halteres&lt;/a&gt; of a house fly, the human brain monitors the tilt feedback from the otoconia constantly in order to keep the head upright and maintain balance during movement. On the contrary, while an airplane’s flight control system uses computers and actuators to aid a pilot in proper flight control, the brain uses rocks and “hairs” … To each their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oup-arc.com/access/content/sensation-and-perception-5e-student-resources/sensation-and-perception-5e-essay-12-1&quot;&gt;Image Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to have a few rocks knocked loose. As a result of either head trauma, advanced age or some other disorder or infection, the otoconia can detach from their membrane and collect along the canals of the inner ear. When this occurs, an individual may have a condition known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/bppv.html&quot;&gt;Benign Paroxysmal Positional Vertigo&lt;/a&gt;, or BPPV, and experience dizziness, nausea, vertigo, lightheadedness and imbalance from loose otoconia. From Oghalai et al., 2000 and Froehling et al, 1991, approximately 50% of all dizziness experienced in those aged 60 and over is due to BPPV. The link &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/movies/Debris-Redistribution.gif&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; features a nicely-done animation of displaced otoconia, and it’s easy to imagine that this condition would be very uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of tests that can be administered to make a diagnosis of BBPV and most of them involve a doctor moving the patient’s head around to shake the otoconia back into place. If you watched Looney Tunes or Tom and Jerry back in the day, then some of these methods may bring these sound effects to mind: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EX4i7at27XU&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EX4i7at27XU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-semont-maneuver&quot;&gt;The Semont Maneuver:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/Semont/semont.html&quot;&gt;dizziness-and-balance.com&lt;/a&gt;, the Semont Maneuver, named for Dr. Alain Semont, involves a high velocity shaking of the head, as the patient moves from lying on one side of their body to the other, also very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 7&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;From the website: “On the diagram…one starts upright (A), goes to “bad” Dix-Hallpike side (B), then one is rapidly “flipped” to “bad” side down (C), there is an optional gentle “rap” of the head against the bed, one remains there for a few minutes, and then sits back up. See: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/dix%20hallpike.htm&quot;&gt;Dix-Hallpike Test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be mentioned that the Semont maneuver is not currently favored in the United States, because these rapid movements are a bit terrifying if you have this condition. However, it is known to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-foster-maneuver&quot;&gt;The “Foster” Maneuver&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based off of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/epley/epley.html&quot;&gt;Epley Maneuver&lt;/a&gt;, the “Foster” Maneuver can be performed at home by patients diagnosed with BPPV and is preferred by many. Diagram:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;From the website: “In 2012, Dr. Carol Foster reported another self-treatment maneuver for posterior canal BPPV, that she subsequently popularized with an online video on youtube. In this maneuver, using the illustrations above that she published in her 2012 article, one begins with head up, then flips to upside down, comes back up into a push-up position with the head turned laterally (actually 45 deg), and then back to sitting upright. The trick of it is that instead of putting the head far backward, one puts the head very far forward. “&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Dr. Timothy C. Hain wrote this section at the bottom of his BPPV &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dizziness-and-balance.com/disorders/bppv/home/home-pc.html&quot;&gt;home treatment page&lt;/a&gt;, which I will copy here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-modest-proposal--another-maneuver-anyone&quot;&gt;A Modest Proposal – Another maneuver anyone?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seems to be considerable willingness in the literature to propose new maneuvers, often named after their inventor, that are simple variants of older maneuvers. Well – there are still a few maneuvers left to adapt (:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one is willing to engage in athletic positions as in the half-somersault procedure, why not just take things to the logical extreme and do a complete backward somersault in the plane of the affected canal, starting from upright (A below), then to the home-Epley bottom position above (B below), then into the Foster position C – midway between B and C below, and then follow through to position C below (which is also position D of the Foster and home Epley), and then finally to upright again. Stopping for 30 seconds in each position. A full circle. This is a home version of the Lembert 360 rotation described in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I propose naming it “The full circle maneuver”. Or maybe the full backwards somersault. We do not recommend that people try this maneuver out – as there are some practical issues (i.e. getting from position B to C) and we would not want anyone to hurt themselves. But it should work just as well as the others, as the positions of the head are the same. And that’s the only thing that matters when one considers the efficiency of these maneuvers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/youve-got-rocks/Picture 9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 9&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0194599800701872&quot;&gt;Oghalai et al., 2000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/2046397&quot;&gt;Froehling et al., 1991&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Mathis</name></author><summary type="html">If you’ve ever seen someone stumbling through the street, you may have thought to yourself, “this person’s off their rocker!” The origin of the phrase is unclear, but perhaps I could provide some insight through a different type of “rock”. It’s hard to believe that the survival of every human depends on rocks—the rocks in your inner ear. Without these rocks, it would be really hard to wake up in the morning and brush your teeth for work (which for some, may be a blessing in disguise). If someone crashed into your car, and the rocks in your ear were knocked loose, you would most definitely be dazed and confused. In general, it would be quite uncomfortable attempting to discern the location of your body or your surroundings or really anything at all. These almighty, glorious and life-saving rocks, called otoconia, live in the inner ear of all humans and fortunately, they allow us to understand that our head is in motion.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rocks.png" /></entry></feed>